export const chapter = "Chapter - 8: Measurement and Motion";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
        {
          question: "What is measurement?",
          optionA:
            "The comparison of an unknown quantity with some known fixed quantity",
          optionB: "The calculation of unknown quantities",
          optionC: "The estimation of random values",
          correctAnswer:
            "The comparison of an unknown quantity with some known fixed quantity",
        },
        {
          question: "What is a unit in measurement?",
          optionA: "A variable value",
          optionB: "A known fixed quantity",
          optionC: "A random number",
          correctAnswer: "A known fixed quantity",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Why were non-standard units of length considered unreliable in ancient times?",
          optionA: "They were too long",
          optionB: "They varied among different people",
          optionC: "They were difficult to use",
          correctAnswer: "They varied among different people",
        },
        {
          question: "When was the International System of Units (SI) adopted?",
          optionA: "1790",
          optionB: "1960",
          optionC: "1890",
          correctAnswer: "1960",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the SI unit of length?",
          optionA: "Centimeter",
          optionB: "Kilogram",
          optionC: "Metre",
          correctAnswer: "Metre",
        },
        {
          question: "How do you convert 2000 meters to kilometers?",
          optionA: "0.2 km",
          optionB: "2 km",
          optionC: "20 km",
          correctAnswer: "2 km",
        },
        {
          question: "Which instrument is used to measure temperature?",
          optionA: "Barometer",
          optionB: "Thermometer",
          optionC: "Hydrometer",
          correctAnswer: "Thermometer",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the SI unit of mass?",
          optionA: "Kilogram",
          optionB: "Gram",
          optionC: "Newton",
          correctAnswer: "Kilogram",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which type of motion involves an object moving along a curved path?",
          optionA: "Linear Motion",
          optionB: "Curvilinear Motion",
          optionC: "Oscillatory Motion",
          correctAnswer: "Curvilinear Motion",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What does a straight line in a distance-time graph indicate?",
          optionA: "Uniform motion",
          optionB: "Random motion",
          optionC: "Rest",
          correctAnswer: "Uniform motion",
        },
      ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
        {
          question:
            "Measurement means the comparison of an unknown quantity with some known fixed quantity of the same kind. The known fixed quantity is called _______.",
          optionA: "Variable",
          optionB: "Benchmark",
          optionC: "Unit",
          correctAnswer: "Unit",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The length of a table is 2 meters. In this measurement, 2 is the _______ and meter is the unit of length.",
          optionA: "Estimate",
          optionB: "Dimension",
          optionC: "Number",
          correctAnswer: "Number",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Long ago, many non-standard units of length were derived from the length of some parts of the human body, such as a pace or footstep. These units are called _______.",
          optionA: "Standard units",
          optionB: "Random units",
          optionC: "Non-standard units",
          correctAnswer: "Non-standard units",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The metric system created by the French in 1790 is an example of _______.",
          optionA: "Dynamic units",
          optionB: "Non-standard units",
          optionC: "Standard units",
          correctAnswer: "Standard units",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The International System of Units, or SI units, was adopted in the year _______.",
          optionA: "1790",
          optionB: "1960",
          optionC: "1890",
          correctAnswer: "1960",
        },
        {
          question: "The SI unit of length is _______.",
          optionA: "Centimeter",
          optionB: "Meter",
          optionC: "Inch",
          correctAnswer: "Meter",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Measuring the length of a room may require the use of a _______.",
          optionA: "Foot ruler",
          optionB: "Measuring tape",
          optionC: "Kilometer scale",
          correctAnswer: "Measuring tape",
        },
        {
          question:
            "While measuring length with a ruler, the eyes should be exactly in front of the point where the measurement is to be taken to avoid _______.",
          optionA: "Precision errors",
          optionB: "Parallax errors",
          optionC: "Systematic errors",
          correctAnswer: "Parallax errors",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The motion of an object when it moves along a curved path is called _______ motion.",
          optionA: "Linear",
          optionB: "Curvilinear",
          optionC: "Oscillatory",
          correctAnswer: "Curvilinear",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The combination of circular and rotational motion is observed when a _______ is opened.",
          optionA: "Bottle cap",
          optionB: "Screw",
          optionC: "Jar lid",
          correctAnswer: "Screw",
        },
      ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
        {
          question:
            "The Nanda dynasty was founded by Mahapadma Nanda before the rise of the Mauryan Empire.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Alexander the Great entered the Indian subcontinent in 326 BC and defeated King Porus between the rivers Jhelum and Chenab.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "We know about the Mauryan rule mainly from three books: the Indica written by Megasthenes, the Arthashastra written by Chanakya, and the Mudrarakshasa written by Vishakhadutta.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Chanakya guided and trained Chandragupta Maurya in various aspects of Warfare, so that their dreams could be realized.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Chandragupta Maurya earned the title of 'Emperor of Bharat' in 321 BC and was known as The Emperor of Bharat.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Chandragupta turned towards the north-west after defeating Seleucus Nicator and expanded his empire. Seleucus Nicator governed the territory that Alexander the Great had left after his invasion and appointed his governor in Egypt.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Mauryan Empire extended from Bengal in the east to the Hindu Kush in the west, and from the Himalayas in the north to the Narmada River in the south.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "After Chandragupta, his son Bindusara became the emperor and ruled from 297 BC to 272 BC. Bindusara is said to have maintained friendly relations with other Dynasties.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Ashoka the Great ascended the Mauryan throne in 272 BC and earned titles like Devanam Priya (beloved of gods) and Priyadarshi (handsome-looking) after his coronation in 269 BC.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Mauryan empire declined within 50 years of Ashoka's death, in 185 BC, when Pushyamitra Sunga overthrew the last Mauryan king due to various factors, including opposition to Buddhism.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
      ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
